Guide to the Montana Attorney General's Office Records 1893-1969
Montana Historical Society Archives
- Dockets (correspondence and other material re cases)
  - Docket #9, case #579: Robert L. Wine and Shirley J. Wine vs. Montana (re storm sewers in Capitol Complex, Helena), 1961-1962 (Box-folder 103 / 55)
  - Docket #10, case #2: Shotgun Acquisition Company vs. Montana (re mining property in Butte), 1962 (Box-folder 103 / 56)
  - Docket #10, case #6: Leo Steward vs. Floyd E. Powell, Register of Motor Vehicles (re resignation; see also case 66), 1962 (Box-folder 103 / 57)
  - Docket #10, case #12: Omar D. Utley Estate (re State's purchase of Estate's mining claims at Montana State College's Red Bluff Ranch), 1960-1961 (Box-folder 103 / 58)
  - Docket #10, case #20: State Industrial Accident Board vs. Orville Weed (re compliance in Big Fork), 1959-1962 (Box-folder 103 / 59)
  - Docket #10, case #21: Charles E. Green vs. Tom Stubbs (re Billings property), 1962 (Box-folder 103 / 60)
  - Docket #10, case #51: Frances Brown vs. Board of Education (re Eastern Montana College teaching contract), 1961-1963 (Box-folder 103 / 61)
  - Docket #10, case #59: Billings Properties, Inc. vs. Yellowstone County (re subdivision regulations), 1962-1966 (Box-folder 103 / 62)
  - Docket #10, case #66: Motors Insurance Company vs. Floyd E. Powell, Register of Motor Vehicles (re resignation; see also case 6), 1962-1964 (Box-folder 103 / 63)
  - Docket #10, case #96: In the matter of James G. Crawford (re disbarment), 1962 (Box-folder 103 / 64)
  - Docket #10, case #97: Montana vs. Keith L. Moran (re Billings burglary), 1963 (Box-folder 103 / 65)
  - Docket #10, case #98: Athan J. Sackapoulos vs. Montana (re Hilton G. Mailman Estate, Harlowton), 1962 (Box-folder 103 / 66)
  - Docket #10, case #104: In the matter of Arthur R. Meyer (re disbarment), 1962 (Box-folder 103 / 67)
  - Docket #10, case #142: R.L. Pattee et al. vs. State Oil and Gas Conservation Commission (re rights of adjoining landowners), 1963-1964 (Box-folder 103 / 68)
  - Docket #10, case #154: Assiniboine and Sioux Tribes of Fort Peck Indian Reservation vs. Calvert Exploration Company and State Oil and Gas Conservation Commission (re pooling agreement in Benrud Field), 1963-1964 (Box-folder 103 / 69)
  - Docket #10, case #158: A.E. Blattner vs. State Board of Education (re accident after Northern Montana College picnic), 1963-1965 (Box-folder 103 / 70)
  - Docket #10, case #172: Montana ex rel. William J. Nelson vs. Edward C. Ellsworth Jr. (re time for good behavior at State Prison), 1962-1963 (Box-folder 103 / 71)
  - Docket #10, case #175: Jacob White Bear Estate (Pine Ridge, S.D.), 1963 (Box-folder 103 / 72)
  - Docket #10, case #179: Gerald F. Davis vs. Montana (re appeal of lewd and lascivious act conviction), 1960 (Box-folder 103 / 73)
  - Docket #10, case #185: Costas A. Watson vs. Charles Carney and State Fire Marshal (re demolition of building in Billings), 1961-1963 (Box-folder 103 / 74)
  - Docket #10, case #196: Rock Creek Ditch and Flume Company vs. Flint Creek Water Users Association, 1963 (Box-folder 103 / 75)
  - Docket #10, case #198: In the matter of Charles L. O'Donnell (re disbarment), 1963 (Box-folder 103 / 76)
  - Docket #10, case #238: In the matter of John J. Tomich (re illegal search), 1963-1964 (Box-folder 103 / 77)
  - Docket #10, case #239: Ingrid Anderson et al. vs. Montana State Board of Health (re nursing homes), 1963 (Box-folder 103 / 78)
  - Docket #10, case #241: Dennis M. Wetzel vs. Montana (re revocation of probation), 1963 (Box-folder 103 / 79)
  - Docket #10, case #246: George Jones vs. Montana (re insanity defense), 1964 (Box-folder 103 / 80)
  - Docket #10, case #249: In the matter of Donald A. Paddock (re disbarment), 1964-1967 (Box-folder 103 / 81)
  - Docket #10, case #262: Dorothy Blanche Fitzgerald vs. State Board of Public Institutions (re facilities at state institutions), 1963-1964 (Box-folder 103 / 82)
  - Docket #10, case #284: Gallatin Canyon Elk Protective Association vs. Lemuel A. Garrison, 1964 (Box-folder 103 / 83)
- Dockets of Land Cases
  - Docket register of land cases in the United States Land Office (contains cases in which Montana was a party), 1894-1913 (Volume Vol. 10)
  - Case #75: A.J. Voight vs. Montana (re land in Glacier County), 1902-1906 (Box-folder 103 / 84)
  - Case #76: Alfred Allison vs. Montana (re land at Cut Bank), 1903-1906 (Box-folder 103 / 85)
  - Case #77: Montana vs. Thomas Almo (re land at Jennings), 1906 (Box-folder 103 / 86)
  - Case #79: Montana vs. Richard M. Christiansen et al. (re land at Jennings), 1905-1906 (Box-folder 103 / 87)
  - Case #80: Montana vs. John M. Olson (re land near Trego), 1905 (Box-folder 103 / 88)
  - Case #83: Montana vs. Leon King et al. (re land at Olney), 1906 (Box-folder 103 / 89)
  - Case #84: Montana vs. Axel L. Anderson (re land near Trout Creek and Missoula), 1905-1906 (Box-folder 103 / 90)
  - Case #100: Montana vs. Jere M. Koch (re land near Culbertson), 1906 (Box-folder 103 / 91)
  - Case #102: In re state lien land selections Gros Ventre Indian Reservation, 1906 (Box-folder 103 / 92)
  - Case #103: State selection list 5 (re land in Kalispell district), 1906-1907 (Box-folder 103 / 93)
  - Case #104: Montana vs. Alonzo P. Hart (re land southwest of Laurel), 1907-1909 (Box-folder 103 / 94)
  - Case #106: In re indemnity school land selections (near Culbertson), 1908-1910 (Box-folder 103 / 95)
  - Case #109: School selection in Forest Reserve (re land near Belton and Glacier Park), 1909 (Box-folder 103 / 96)
  - Case #110: In the matter of election by Montana to take patent for certain lands, reserving to U.S. the coal thereon, 1909 (Box-folder 103 / 97)
  - Case #111: In re indemnity school land selections (re rules 3 and 7), 1910 (Box-folder 103 / 98)
  - Case #115: In re application of Charles D. Wooster et al. (re lands on Flathead Indian Reservation), 1909-1910 (Box-folder 103 / 99)
  - Case #117: In re application of Fred W. Handel and Mae Handel (re coal lands east of Roundup), 1910-1912 (Box-folder 103 / 100)
  - Case #118: In re protests against state land selections on Flathead Indian Reservation, 1911 (Box-folder 103 / 101)
  - Case #122: J.B. Huber vs. State of Montana (re land northeast of Inverness), 1911 (Box-folder 103 / 102)
  - Case #123: In re application of William Coffman (re land near Culbertson), 1911 (Box-folder 103 / 103)
- Undocketed cases (correspondence related to cases)
  - State land selections near Billings, 1903 (Box-folder 103 / 104)
  - In re water ditches in connection with School for Deaf and Blind, Boulder, 1903-1904 (Box-folder 103 / 105)
  - Montana vs. American Smelting and Refining Company, 1906, 1908 (Box-folder 103 / 106)
  - Montana vs. ____ Knapp (re extradition in Missoula larceny case), 1907 (Box-folder 103 / 107)
  - Lincoln County vs. Coast Bridge Company and National Surety Company (re collapse of bridge at Rexford), 1912-1916 (Box-folder 103 / 108)
  - Montana vs. Great Northern Railway Company (re sheep shipments), 1913-1914 (Box-folder 103 / 109)
  - Investigation of Dawson County Attorney Joseph A. Slattery (re issuance of wholesale liquor license), 1914 (Box-folder 103 / 110)
  - Charles Allen Watt Estate (re black sheepherder in Yellowstone County), 1915 (Box-folder 103 / 111)
  - J.E. Templeton Bankruptcy (re State Grain Inspector), 1915 (Box-folder 103 / 112)
  - Montana vs. Felkner Haynes, Rosebud County Attorney (re gambling cases), 1917-1918 (Box-folder 103 / 113)
  - Montana vs. Charles Franklin (re land at Divide), 1917-1918 (Box-folder 103 / 114)
  - Montana vs. ____ Grogrud (re liquor at Havre), 1918-1919 (Box-folder 103 / 115)
  - State Land Office vs. Clifford Jones (re land near Red Lodge), 1918-1919, 1924 (Box-folder 103 / 116)
  - Montana vs. E. Koeford vs. Hill County Commissioners (re creation of Liberty County), 1919 (Box-folder 103 / 117)
  - Montana vs. Fred Sherer (re murder in Wheatland County), 1919 (Box-folder 103 / 118)
  - Montana vs. Ed Nelson (re arson in Scobey), 1920, 1922 (Box-folder 103 / 119)
  - Toole County Commissioners investigation (re alleged misconduct in office; also includes annotated list of grand jurors and information on murder at Sweet Grass), 1922 (Box-folder 103 / 120)
  - State Treasurer vs. Banks (re corporation license tax), 1922-1923 (Box-folder 103 / 121)
  - Montana vs. M.D. Boyce (re kidnapping in custody dispute), 1925 (Box-folder 103 / 122)
  - Montana vs. Pat Roddy (re liquor in Kalispell), 1925 (Box-folder 103 / 123)
  - ____ Rohr vs. Stanton Trust and Savings Bank of Great Falls (re voluntary liquidation), 1925-1926 (Box-folder 103 / 124)
  - Montana vs. George Thienes (re liquor in Glasgow), 1926 (Box-folder 103 / 125)
  - Nellie Bradford Estate, Columbus, 1926, 1928 (Box-folder 103 / 126)
  - U.S. Canton vs. Valley County et al. (re creation of cattle roundup district), 1927 (Box-folder 103 / 127)
  - Homestake Exploration Company vs. W.H. Schoregge et al. (re taxation), 1927 (Box-folder 103 / 128)
  - Bess C. Potts vs. State et al. (re loss of Golden Valley County funds in bank failure), 1927 (Box-folder 103 / 129)
  - Montana ex rel. Harry W. Sankey vs. Arthur Markley (re Garfield County printing contracts), 1927 (Box-folder 103 / 130)
  - Montana ex rel. D.M. Kelly vs. State Savings Bank of Butte (re unclaimed dividends), 1927 (Box-folder 103 / 131)
  - Gasoline tax collection cases (includes reports of field audits), 1927-1933 (Box-folder 103 / 132)
  - Flathead River power site case (re rights of Indians and economic impact of proposed dam below Polson), 1928 (Box-folder 103 / 133)
  - Montana vs. Henry Anderson (re elk hunting), 1928 (Box-folder 103 / 134)
  - Montana vs. Oscar R. Zachary (re kidnapping in custody dispute), 1928-1929 (Box-folder 103 / 135)
  - Malta National Bank vs. Phillips County (re taxation), 1929 (Box-folder 103 / 136)
  - Rainbow Refining Company (re taxation), 1929-1930 (Box-folder 103 / 137)
  - John and Peter Anderson vs. Madison County (re sheep assessment), 1930 (Box-folder 103 / 138)
  - In the matter of L.O. Caswell (re disbarment), 1930 (Box-folder 103 / 139)
  - Montana vs. Louis Davidson (re perjury), 1930 (Box-folder 103 / 140)
  - Montana vs. Continental Oil Company (re price-fixing), 1930 (Box-folder 103 / 141)
  - J.V. Weber vs. City of Helena (re water bonds), 1930 (Box-folder 103 / 142)
  - Investigation into death of Frank S. Metzel (Madison County sheriff), 1930-1931 (Box-folder 103 / 143)
  - Montana vs. Anna M. Arnot (re murder in Glasgow), 1930-1932 (Box-folder 103 / 144)
  - First State Bank, Plevna (re Cabin Creek gas lands), 1930-1959 (Box-folder 103 / 145)
  - In the matter of Sun River Chateau and Livestock Company, 1931 (Box-folder 103 / 146)
  - State Industrial Accident Board vs. Town of Eureka, 1931, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 103 / 147)
  - American Legion vs. Judith Basin County (re exemption from taxation), 1931-1933 (Box-folder 103 / 148)
  - Montana vs. E.G. Harris (re bribery of juror), 1932-1933 (Box-folder 103 / 149)
  - Dakota Montana Oil Company vs. Toole County (re oil assessment), 1933 (Box-folder 103 / 150)
  - Glendive State Bank vs. Dawson County (re taxes paid under protest), 1933 (Box-folder 103 / 151)
  - Nels Sandberg Estate, Long Beach, California, 1933 (Box-folder 103 / 152)
  - Western Loan and Building Company (re reorganization), 1933 (Box-folder 103 / 153)
  - Occident Elevator Company vs. Montana Dakota Grain Company, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 103 / 154)
  - Brobaugh et al. vs. Stafford et al. (re Walsh Grain Company, Bozeman), 1934 (Box-folder 104 / 1)
  - Milwaukee County vs. M.E. white Company (re taxation of foreign corporations), 1934-1935 (Box-folder 104 / 2)
  - Montana vs. Jack Partington (re damage to Laurel bridge), 1934-1935 (Box-folder 104 / 3)
  - Wyomont Producing and Refining Company (re taxation), 1934-1936 (Box-folder 104 / 4)
  - A.J. Fousek et al. vs. Harry Hogan et al. (re fire department platoons, Great Falls), 1935 (Box-folder 104 / 5)
  - Kentucky Whip and Collar Company vs. Illinois Central Railroad Company (re prison labor), 1935 (Box-folder 104 / 6)
  - C.L. Moser vs. C.H. Kester (re grain business in Valier), 1935 (Box-folder 104 / 7)
  - Montana vs. J.A. Snell (re sale of wheat), 1936 (Box-folder 104 / 8)
  - Frank H. Johnson, State Superintendent of Banks vs. W.V. Kaiser (re First State Bank of Plevna and Montana-Dakota Utilities), 1936-1954 (Box-folder 104 / 9)
  - In the matter of application for grazing privileges of J.W. and M.G. Aker, Arizona, 1937 (Box-folder 104 / 10)
  - Montana vs. Fred Christa (re hail insurance), 1937-1938 (Box-folder 104 / 11)
  - First State Bank, Plevna (re liquidation), 1937-1954 (Box-folder 104 / 12)
  - Frank H. Livingston vs. Wolf Point Superintendent of Schools (re termination of contract), 1937-1942 (Box-folder 104 / 13)
  - Nebraska vs. Wyoming and Colorado (re water rights), 1938 (Box-folder 104 / 14)
  - Montana vs. Beulah McBroom (re fishing licenses), 1939-1940 (Box-folder 104 / 15)
  - Price Brooks Company vs. Ike Brady (re horticulture permit), 1940 (Box-folder 104 / 16)
  - Montana ex rel. Harrison Freebourn vs. Paul S. Standley and Lewis and Clark County Commissioners (re lack of qualifications for office), 1940 (Box-folder 104 / 17)
  - Veterans and Pioneer Memorial Building bonds (re test case on validity of bonds--Montana Historical Society building), 1941 (Box-folder 104 / 18)
  - Fitzsimmons vs. Leonard G. Clark, deputy game warden, Hill County (re conversion of furs), 1941 (Box-folder 104 / 19)
  - State Insane Hospital bonds (re test case on validity of bonds), 1941 (Box-folder 104 / 20)
  - Lincoln County vs. Eldon J. Schuck, county clerk, and Austin Fraxer, county treasurer (re fire assessments for private landowners on National Forest), 1941 (Box-folder 104 / 21)
  - James H.T. Ryman Estate, Missoula County, 1941 (Box-folder 104 / 22)
  - Estate of Margaret P. Daly, Hamilton, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 104 / 23)
  - J.H. Hamilton Company and Oil Royalty Company lease hearings, 1942 (Box-folder 104 / 24)
  - State Water Conservation Board vs. Ravalli Land and Irrigation Company (re proposed board assumption of assets of company; includes articles of incorporation, 1901), 1942 (Box-folder 104 / 25)
  - In the matter of the Miller Land and Livestock Company (re taxation of imported goods), 1942 (Box-folder 104 / 26)
  - Madison County School District 7 vs. Sye B. White et al. (re Jehovah's Witnesses' refusal to salute flag), 1942-1943 (Box-folder 104 / 27)
  - Robert Hutchinson Estate; Charles G. Johnson Estate (re property of Norwegian nationals during World War II), 1943 (Box-folder 104 / 28)
  - Montana vs. Fred Ellis; Montana vs. Gerald Whitmore (re statutory rape, Fort Harrison), 1943 (Box-folder 104 / 29)
  - United States vs. Evora Roberta Stevens (re Buffalo Rapids Project), 1944 (Box-folder 104 / 30)
  - Escheted estate proceedings (re state acquisition of estates unclaimed for more than ten years), 1944-1946 (Box-folder 104 / 31)
  - Mae Keith vs. A.G. Fousek, Trustee et al. (re inheritance tax on Lincoln County property), 1946 (Box-folder 104 / 32)
  - Sage Creek boundary waters case (re appropriation rights between United States and Canada; includes correspondence, background information, and reports), 1946-1957 (Box-folder 104 / 33-35)
  - State vs. Paul Brown (re counterfeit revenue stamps), 1947 (Box-folder 104 / 36)
  - International Joint Commission hearings (re Waterton-Belly River Project; includes correspondence and reports), 1947-1955 (Box-folder 104 / 37-38)
  - Mountain States Telephone and Telegraph rate increase application: PSC #3802 (1948-1950); PSC #3940 (1951-1952), 1948-1952 (Box-folder 104 / 39)
  - Missouri River Basin Survey Commission (re constitutional limitation of state and local governments to participate in land and water resource development; includes reports, correspondence, etc.), 1949-1953 (Box-folder 104 / 40)
  - Gas rate case (re Montana-Dakota Utilities Company; Montana-Wyoming Gas Pipe Line Company; Mondakota Gas Company et al.), 1949-1955 (Box-folder 104 / 41)
  - Columbia Basin Interstate Compact Commission, 1950 (Box-folder 104 / 42)
  - International Joint Commission hearing (re Libby Dam), 1950-1951 (Box-folder 104 / 43)
  - Montana Power Company application to import Canadian natural gas: public opinion, 1951 (Box-folder 104 / 44)
  - Public utilities rates: public opinion, 1951-1955 (Box-folder 104 / 45)
  - Montana vs. Robert Chamberlain (re gasoline tax refund fraud), 1951-1953 (Box-folder 104 / 46)
  - Montana vs. Howard E. Hill (re gasoline tax refund fraud), 1951-1954 (Box-folder 104 / 47)
  - Montana vs. Medric LaRoque (re gasoline tax refund fraud), 1951-1953 (Box-folder 104 / 48)
  - Montana vs. J.C. Lynch (re gasoline tax refund fraud), 1951 (Box-folder 104 / 49)
  - Montana vs. Pat Maloney (re gasoline tax refund fraud), 1951-1954 (Box-folder 104 / 50)
  - Montana vs. Judge George W. Padbury (re gasoline tax refund fraud), 1951, 1954 (Box-folder 104 / 51)
  - Montana vs. John Phillips (re gasoline tax refund fraud), 1951, 1954 (Box-folder 104 / 52)
  - Montana vs. Theodore Tomlinson (re gasoline tax refund fraud), 1951 (Box-folder 104 / 53)
  - Gasoline tax refund fraud cases (includes statements of witnesses, reports of investigations, modis operandi, etc.), 1951-1954 (Box-folder 104 / 54-55)
  - Pine Field Unit Agreement (re oil and gas development on State land in Phillips County), 1953-1954 (Box-folder 104 / 56)
  - Montana intrastate freight rates and changes (ICC Docket #31620), 1955 (Box-folder 104 / 57)
  - Big Coulee Unit Agreement (re oil and gas development on State land in Stillwater and Golden Valley counties), 1957-1961 (Box-folder 104 / 58)
  - North Gildford Gas Field Pooling Agreement, 1959 (Box-folder 104 / 59)
  - Albert Leuthold, State Superintendent of Banks vs. William B. Wing, Controller of Currency (re merger of First National Bank of Butte and Daly Bank of Anaconda), 1966-1968 (Box-folder 104 / 60)
  - State agencies: structure, powers, duties, etc., undated (Box-folder 104 / 61)
- Financial Records
  - Ledger, 1905-1940 (Volume Vol. 11)
  - Ledgers, 1941-1969 (Box-folder 105 / 1-5)
  - Statement of bonds and securities passed upon, 1906-1938 (Volume Vol. 12)
  - Abstract register (includes legal description of land, name of applicant, price, date paid, and name of abstractor), 1921-1941 (Volume Vol. 13)
  - List of maps transferred to Library Map Collection; list of photographs transferred to Photo Archives; list of artifacts transferred to Museum (Box-folder 105 / 6)